I
我
code with our reactive reference in setup
在setup中用我们响应式的ref编码
and now is how do we add a method
接下来演示如何添加方法
with our regular component syntax if we wanted to increase capacity
如果我们用常规组件语法想增加容量
might create a method that looks like this
可能会创建一个如下所示的方法
what might this look like using our new syntax
使用我们新语法会是什么样子呢
first
第一
inside of the template
在模板里面
let's add a button
我们添加一个按钮
it calls this method
它调用此方法
simple enough
足够简单
to create a method using our new syntax
想要使用新语法创建该方法
we declare a normal function in setup method
我们要在setup里面声明一个普通函数
we then need to return it from our setup method
然后我们需要从setup方法里返回它
because our template access to it
因为我们的模板会访问它
what goes inside of our increased capacity function
我们增加capacity的函数内部要写点什么？
your first guess might be capacity plus plus
猜测可能是capacity自加
however this is not going to work it's going to error out
但是这行不通，会报一个错出来
because we can't increase an object
因为我们不能增加一个对象
remember this is a a reactive reference and not a primitive
记住它是一个响应式的Ref，不是原始值
if we inspected capacity in the console, we would see that its a reference with a getter and a setter
如果我们在控制台中输出capacity，会发现它是一个带getter和setter的reference对象
and also has this value property
且有一个value属性
which is what we need to access
这才是我们需要访问的
to increment capacity we call capacity to value plus plus
为了增加capacity，我们调用capacity.value++
this is how we access the value on a reactive reference
这就是我们如何访问Ref上的值
we jump in our browser
我们切到浏览器
we can see our Button increase capacity
可以看见按钮增加了capacity
at this point I was wondering and you might be too
此时我想你和我一样想要知道
why don't we need to call that value in the template when we print out capacity
为什么我们在模板中打印capacity时不需要调用这个value呢？
well it turns out that when vue find a ref in the template
事实证明当vue在模板中找到一个ref
it will automatically expose the inner value
它会自动暴露内部的value
so you should never need to call dot value
所以你永远不需要调用.value
inside the template
在模板中